



linkedin.com/in/josef-gabrielsson





www.josef.st

gabrielsson@josef.st

## Josef Gabrielsson | CV

2022-04-29

#### **SUMMARY**



Josef is a Unicorn Developer and Manager with an entrepreneurial background. He has worked professionally in IT since 2005 in different fields such as development, design, engineering, management, business, infrastructure, in both the public and private sectors.

Josef has a 2-year diploma in object-oriented programming with a focus on .NET and Java, but has worked as a full-stack developer for most of his career using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, and occasionally .NET, Go, Python and Java.

Josef is a person who is future driven and very passionate about what he is doing and aims for productivity and perfection in everything he does.

Josef's goal is to master all processes, frameworks, methodologies, standard principles, and core activities so that he one day may become a great leader at a world-leading company.

#### **COMPETENCE OVERVIEW**

**Experienced roles** 10+ years as web developer

10+ years as server technician 10+ years as UX/UI designer 5+ years as system developer 2+ years as app developer 5+ years as devOps engineer

Programming languages Bash, C, C#, CSS, Go, HTML, Java, JavaScript, PHP, Python, Visual Basic,

XML, UML, YAML

Programming frameworks & ORM .NET, EF, Codelgniter, Django, F3, Hibernate, Laravel, Spring, GIN

**Programming libraries** React, jQuery, Front

**Design patterns & architectures** 3-tier, Monolithic, MVC, MVP, MVVM

Platforms & Cloud platforms .NET Core, .NET Standard, Android, Azure, Drupal, GitHub, GitLab,

WordPress, OpenShift

Databases MariaDB, MSSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, MS Access, PostgreSQL

Web servers Apache, NGINX, IIS

Tools Android Studio, Basecamp, Docker, Eclipse, GIT, Illustrator, Jira, Maven,

Mockito, Monday, MySQL Workbench, NGINX, Node, Pencil, Projectplace, Photoshop, Pivotal tracker, PowerShell, Slack, Teams, TortoiseSVN, Trello, Visual Code, Visual Paradigm, Visual Studio, XD

**Practices** ATDD, CI, CD, DDD, EER modeling, PP, Service design, Stand-up, TDD

Methodologies & frameworks DevOps, Kanban, Lean, Scrum

**Operating systems** DOS, FreeBSD, Linux, Windows, Windows Server

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **2021 - Current**

Permanent employment

## IT Service, Consid, IT Consultant Developer & DevOps

Developing and implementing software for customer as consultant.

- Developing Back-end with PHP.
- Developing Front-end with React, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS.
- Refactoring code.
- Reviewing code with Bitbucket.
- Refining issues in backlog with Jira.
- Managing Cloud Computing with OpenShift.

## 2018 - 2020

Permanent employment

#### Software Development, Göteborgsregionen, Sofware Developer & DevOps

Developing and leading in-house projects using a variety of technologies and tools, setting up a new infrastructure and taking responsibility, working along with distributed teams across the organization, and collaborating with external partners.

- Developing Back-end with C#, Go, PHP.
- Developing Front-end with <u>React</u>, <u>Angular</u>, <u>JavaScript</u>, <u>HTML</u>, <u>CSS</u>.
- Developing and automating processes with Excel.
- Implementing agile with Kanban Framework using Teams Planner and Trello.
- Implementing DevOps using Docker, Nagios, Teams, Flow, Gitlab, and Azure.
- Implementing Package management for several projects.
- Facilitating and mentoring personal.
- Monitoring, installing, troubleshooting, and securing IT Infrastructure.
- Managing Cloud Computing with Azure and Gitlab.
- Managing Product Backlog with Azure boards and Trello.
- Applying interactive and visual design principles.
- Approaching code first with Entity Framework.
- Approaching Service design.
- Solving business problems.

#### 2016 - 2018

Permanent employment

#### IT Service, Castra, IT Consultant Developer & Mentor

Developing and designing software as consultant, internally supporting, mentoring and coaching sales team, helping them with it-terms, processes, and strategies.

Interviewing and recruiting new consultant candidates together with HR personal.

- Developing Back-end with C#, Java, Swift, Python, PHP.
- Developing Front-end with JavaScript (Ionic, jQuery, Vanilla), HTML, CSS.
- Modeling and designing diagrams for MySQL/MariaDB, PostgreSQL.
- Developing and implementing API.
- Facilitating and mentoring personal.
- Managing private servers on-premises.
- Interviewing consult candidates.
- Managing and mastering Product Backlog with Pivotal tracker.
- Applying interactive and visual design principles.
- Approaching code first with Hibernate Framework.
- Approaching code of conduct.
- Solving business problems.

#### 2014 - 2015

Permanent employment

## Software Development, Resdirekt, Web Developer & Mobile Developer

Developing Android and PHP hybrid solution search engine for flights and hotels. Working in a small team in-house together with a project manager and a UX/UI designer.

- Developing Back-end with PHP, Java (Android).
- Developing Front-end with JavaScript (jQuery), HTML, CSS.
- Integrating with Expedia API.
- Manipulating DOM elements from Dohop.
- Managing Product Backlog with Basecamp.
- Approaching Service design.
- Solving business problems.

#### 2005 - 2013

Self-employment

## IT Service, Aleptra, IT Consultant Developer

Self-employed developing and implementing full-cycle software for the company and my customers. Working alone or with different teams in different industries. Hosting customers in a small Data Center powered by Dell Xeon servers running Linux and FreeBSD.

- Developing Back-end with Bash, C, VB, ASP, PHP.
- Developing Front-end with JavaScript (Vanilla), HTML & CSS.
- Implementing API:s.
- Modeling and designing diagrams for MySQL/MariaDB.
- Applying interactive and visual design principles.
- Managing Service design.
- Managing requirements.
- Managing businesses with customers.
- Managing and running a small Data Center in Stockholm.
- Offering services like DNS, FTP, web analytics.
- Solving business problems.

#### **ASSIGNMENT EXPERIENCE**

#### 2021/04 - Current

Duration: 1 year & x months

**Software Development, University of Gothenburg, Full-stack Developer & DevOps** PHP Drupal, and React development of existing multisite solution. Working together with a scrum team.

#### 2020/03 - 2020/05

Duration: 2 months

Software Development, Göteborgsregionen, Full-stack GIS Developer & DevOps

.NET and React development of a plugin that can measure carbon dioxide emissions over different selected areas for Hajk (GIS solution based on OpenLayers). Pipelining a CI/CD with Azure DevOps using YAML to deploy the application.

#### 2019/06 - 2019/07

Duration: 1 month

Software Development, Göteborgsregionen, Full-stack Developer & DevOps

.NET development, UI/UX design, and implementation of a webpage with MVC called Skolmuseet, listing old artifacts items, links, and articles. Pipelining a CI/CD with Azure DevOps using YAML to deploy the application.

## 2019/01 - 2019/06

Duration: 3 months

Software Development, Fujitsu & Avanade, Front-end Developer & DevOps

.NET development of the high school admission system called Indra. Designing and implementing the whole non-responsive part with JavaScript, CSS media queries, and ASP.NET Razor. Working together with Fujitsu and Avanade as one united team.

#### 2018/10 - 2019/01

Duration: 1 month

Software Development, Textäventyr, Full-stack Developer & DevOps

Go development, UI/UX development, YAML Pipelining a CI/CD with GitLab. The tool is used to create advanced text-based stories and strongly linked to the Swedish educational system.

#### 2018/09 - 2018/09

Duration: 1 week

## Software Engineering, Göteborgsregionen, Excel Developer

VBA Macro development and implementing invoice auto-generator supporting thousands of opening tabs. Making the Economy department save weeks of manual work.

## 2018/03 - 2020/05

Duration: 2 years & 2 months

## Software Development, Yrkesresan, Drupal Developer & System analyst

PHP Drupal development of a Learning Management System. Large Focus on areas that span the organization. Turning an MVP into a reliable product later contributed to European Social Services Awards (ESSA).

## 2017/02 - 2017/06

Duration: 3 months

#### Software Development, Jordbruksverket, Back-end Developer

Java EE test-driven development of new features for a case management system and financial management system. Implementing new features, writing unit, and integration tests. Working with a large team of managers, developers, and testers.

## 2016/11 – 2017-02

Duration: 3 months

## Software Development, Essity (SCA), Front-end Developer

.NET development in 3 different distributed scrum teams around the world collaborating. Main focus on front-end development of new features for TENA retail system using ASP.NET Razor, JavaScript, and CSS.

## 2016/10 – 2016/11

Duration: 1 month

## Software Development, VIP, Mobile App GIS Developer & Scrum Master

lonic development and UI and implementation of an MVP Data-driven GIS solution based on Google Maps. Real-time monitoring and booking of parking spots. Managing my in-house team of junior developers.

## 2016/09 - 2016/10

Duration: 1 month

## Sofware Development, Biometric, Mobile App Developer & Scrum Master

Apache Cordova development and implementation of biometric authentication based on voice and camera recognition as MVP. Managing my in-house team of junior developers.

#### 2016/08

#### Support, M2, IT Technician

Duration: 1 day

Installation of extra routers and access points. Opening ports in Fortigate and installing a Windows Server on-premises so it can be used as a Test server. Migrating data from the NAS server to the Cloud (Office 365).

#### 2016/06

#### **Education, Newton, IT Lecturer**

Duration: 3 days

Lecturing students in the classroom about Content Management System in this case WordPress. Creating a PowerPoint presentation and demonstrating live how the CMS works and finishing with answering technical and friendly questions.

2016/01 - 2016/10

#### Software Engineering, E-gov LLC, System Engineer & Scrum Master

Android, iOS, PHP, Python development, UX/UI design, and database design implementation of a hybrid solution for hotel room service, API, test cases with PHP, Python, and Locust. Collaborating with engineers in Dubai and managing my inhouse team of junior developers.

2012/01 - 2012/02

# Software Engineering, Videofemman, Embedded System Engineer & UI designer VB.NET development, UI design, and database design implementation of an MVP retail system for customers to use on an embedded device. Implementing API and

CMS, Database driven with MSSQL.

2011-02 - 2011/03

## Design & Visualization, Abeer Nehme, Graphic Designer

Designing CD covers and posters using Illustrator and Photoshop for a popular and famous singer and musicologist from the middle east. Collaborating with the artist and her manager.

2011/02 - 2011/03

#### Software Engineering, Suryoyo Sat, Full-Stack Developer

PHP development, UX/UI design, and database design implementation of a webpage for an Aramean Satellite TV channel. Customized CMS. Development of features like membership, contact forms, TV Guide, and video, article publishing.

2010/07 - 2011/02

#### Software Engineering, Klinikregistret, Full-Stack Engineer, SEO-specialist.

PHP development and UI development of advanced register listing clinics in Sweden. Implementation of an advanced CMS, forum. Major focus on SEO optimizations. Working together with a UI/UX designer and stakeholders.

2009/10 - 2011/12

## Software Engineering, FoxFarmaci, Full-Stack Engineer/Designer

PHP development, UX/UI design implementation of medical journal system for vaccinated patients. Managing requirements and planning together with the product owner.

2009/08 - 2009/10

## Software Engineering, Hair Online, Full-Stack Engineer/Designer

PHP development, UX/UI design, and database design implementation of advanced eCommerce selling hair products. Development of features like discounts, and profit formula. Gathering requirements from the product owner.

2009/05 - 2009/06

## Software Engineering, Basilica, Full-Stack Developer/Designer

PHP development and UI/UX design implementation of a simple restaurant webpage driven by a custom file-based CMS for one of the franchisees, listing the whole À la carte menu, offering newsletter.

2008/04 - 2009/02

#### Software Engineering, Dmesta, Full-Stack Developer/Designer

PHP development, UI/UX design, and database design implementation of an Online deal marketplace. Developing features and Integrating with SMS Gateway. Working together with a requirements manager and stakeholders.

2008/03 - 2008/03

## Software Engineering, Blicka Vision, Full-Stack Developer/Designer

PHP development, UX/UI design, and database design implementation of a simple webpage for a production studio. Developing a showcase with embedded production movies and company profile pages.

2008/02 - 2008/03

## Software Engineering, Shell, Full-Stack Developer/Designer

PHP development and UX/UI design implementation of a simple webpage driven by a custom file-based CMS for one of Shell's local petrol stations, listing products, opening hours, and information.

2007/02

#### Software Engineering, CDON, Back-end Developer

ASP development and implementation of a code snippet randomizing 300 thousand unique keys and storing them in an MSSQL database for CDON customers to use in a campaign.

2007/01

## Software Development, Finest, Back-end Developer

OO PHP development and implementation of new features for a social network blog site making it possible for members to favourize and block each other.

2006

## Software Development, Teknikgymnasiet, Full-Stack Developer/Designer

PHP development, UI/UX design, and database design implementation of a whole high school portal as my school project. Working with requirements and planning together with the teacher.

2005

## Software Development, Restaurang Alanya, Full-Stack Developer/Designer

ASP development, UI/UX design, database design (MS Access) implementation of a restaurant webpage solution showing information, listing the whole À la carte menu, and offering a newsletter. It was made during my first work experience.

## **EDUCATION, TRAINING & QUALIFICATIONS**

2016 – 2018	Humanus College   Partly as a distance program Higher Vocational Education — Object-Oriented System Developer (.NET and Java)
2015 – 2016	University of Gothenburg   Evening courses  Business Planning for High-Growth Start-Ups, Ethnoastronomy, The Evolution of the Universe
	KTH Royal Institute of Technology   Distance courses Physical Chemistry for Professionally Active, General Chemistry for Professionally Active
2014 – 2015	Municipal Adult Education   High School Courses SCHOOL LEAVING CERTIFICATE
2003 - 2006	Highschool of Technology   Program FINAL GRADE

## PERSONAL INFORMATION

Personal qualities respectful, humble, responsible, communicative, result-oriented, detail-oriented.

Interests and hobbies Painting, cobbling, psychology, music, watching sci-fi-series/movies, playing mobile

games, reading ancient history

Nationality Swedish

Languages Swedish (fluent), English (fluent), Aramaic (fluent)

Year of birth 1987

Place of birth Södertälje, Sweden